This trick of mine will definitely work.
Do you know what my trick's
key point is?
You need a thick skin.
And you must be persistent.
Persistent.
My bad. I'll go try again.
Jia, Yan.
Jiajia.
I feel like something's off with him today.
Really? What's wrong?
I don't know either.
It's baffling.
I feel there's definitely a problem.
Being overly attentive for no reason
means he's up to no good.
Something's not right.
Definitely not right.
Jiajia.
Has the time issue with low-energy orbit transfer
been solved?
There will be more mission requirements in the future,
so the low-energy transfer orbit
will be used long-term.
However, we haven't abandoned other options.
Hear me out, okay?
Okay.
For the upcoming missions,
I'm thinking of
having these four newcomers
assist you in completing them.
They are young, enthusiastic, and full of ideas.
What they lack is experience and opportunities.
You guys work hard. Don't let me down.
Rest assured.
We are already devoted and passionate,
just waiting to make our mark.
Don't rush.
Heavier tasks
will come with the arrival of the new leader.
New leader?
Who?
General Manager Gu from Xi'an Flight Control
has officially been transferred here
as the Haoyue 4 mission's
one of the chief designers.
He will work with us
to complete the Xingqiao Mission together.
Qin.
My name is Gu Lifeng.
Starting today,
as the chief commander of Haoyue 4,
Mr. Qin and I will lead the team together
to complete the Xingqiao Project.
No need to clap.
Come on, introduce yourselves.
Hello, everyone.
I am from
Beijing Institute of Space Technology,
associate senior engineer Zhang Ziming.
I will be working with you all from now on.
Nice to meet you all.
I am from Xi'an Flight Control,
the chief designer, Jiang Mengyao.
I'm a Scorpio,
and I like milk tea and hot pot.
Unlike Mr. Gu and Mr. Zhang,
everyone here is a stranger to me.
I hope to get to know you all soon.
And I hope in our future work,
you can take good care of me.
Welcome Mr. Gu, Mr. Zhang,
and Ms. Jiang to join us.
I look forward to learning from you all.
Welcome, welcome.
You brighten up the whole institute.
Well, Old Qin,
is the work going smoothly now?
It will definitely be smoother now that you're here.
Okay, good.
You guys continue.
I heard
this Mr. Jiang
is Old Gu's top warrior.
He was selected directly from school back then,
and became a manager half a year earlier than Sister Jia.
Here is your milk tea.
Thank you.
Swiping now.
All set.
If you have time to worry about this,
you might as well think about how to work hard.
Please swipe your card.
True.
The biggest problem now is...
We are Old Qin's soldiers.
It's hard being caught between two big forces.
We'd better behave ourselves from now on.
You're all here.
Mr. Jiang.
Have a seat.
Thank you. Please, sit.
I saw you guys coming in from a distance.
I came from Xi'an in a hurry this time.
I didn't have time to bring any local specialties.
I prepared a small gift for each of you.
I hope you like them.
Yours.
Thank you, Mr. Jiang.
Thank you.
Mr. Jiang, you're too polite.
We didn't prepare any gifts for you,
but you got us something.
How about this?
Next time you have time, you treat us to a meal.
No,
we'll treat you to a meal, okay?
There's no need to be so polite.
This is just a bookmark from the Xi'an Museum.
It's just a small gift.
You are Ying Ziqi.
Yes, I am.
My best friend is currently working on
Professor Qiao's project.
Professor Qiao talks about you all the time.
I've also read your master's thesis.
Your multi-window launch trajectory design
for the same mission is quite unique.
How about this.
Let's add each other on WeChat.
If we get the chance,
we can go visit Professor Qiao together.
Okay.
Well...
How about this?
I'll create a group chat
and invite Mr. Jiang.
It'll be easier for us to communicate.
How does that sound?
Sure.
You're always so thoughtful.
Cai Bo'ao.
I've heard you were at Flight Control.
We finally meet.
When I was in college,
I really admired Academician Cai.
I even audited his classes.
And your father, Professor Cai,
once went to Xi'an
to guide our work.
It's fate that we can work
on the same mission.
Tell me,
are they both doing well?
They're doing great.
That's good.
All right.
I'll leave you to it.
Bye, Mr. Jiang.
Bye, Mr. Jiang. Take care.
Professor Cai.
Academician Cai.
Then may I ask which Cai you are?
I'm just a nobody.
Just Xiao Cai.
Can we just talk nicely?
Aren't we brothers?
Wei, I really didn't lie to you.
Just listen to me.
Yes.
My dad is Professor Cai.
And my grandpa is Academician Cai.
I am a third-generation aerospace worker.
But I really didn't ride on their coattails at all.
I'm not lying to you.
You don't understand my pain at all.
Qi.
Can you say something?
You should believe me, right?
I really didn't lie to you.
My mom said
that if I don't get a PhD,
I'll be the one in the Cai family
with the lowest degree.
My dad said if I don't work in aerospace,
I'd be wasting our aerospace genes.
Also, the number of times I see my grandpa
is pitifully small.
How am I riding on their coattails?
How could I?
I really didn't lie to you.
You guys don't understand my pain at all.
How am I riding on their coattails?
If I do well,
it's expected of me.
I'm a Cai.
A third-generation aerospace worker.
If I don't do well...
I just can't do poorly.
Always making me talk.
What is there to say?
You completely don't understand my pain.
If you had said so earlier,
we wouldn't have given you such a hard time.
I had no idea you had so many difficulties.
Alright.
Show Bao more love from now on.
Okay.
The first flight mission still depends on performance.
Let's work hard together.
We'll participate together,
and celebrate our success.
Great.
Then Team Muxing...
Team Muxing...
Let's go!
Don't touch my flowers.
I haven't seen you in so many years.
Ready to put on a second act here?
Plants have their own personalities too.
If you raise them like this,
you'll ruin them sooner or later.
You don't know a thing.
Look here, here.
Pampered and spoiled.
Do you know what this is?
What is it?
I designed this myself.
An automatic watering and lighting system.
I have to say, we haven't seen each other for years.
Why do I feel like
you're giving off
such strong old man vibes?
Are you going through menopause?
Sure, you're young.
On your Moments,
you always post those pretentious poems.
Those doggerels of yours make no sense.
Stop embarrassing yourself.
Why don't you write some for me to read?
Are you done?
- You begged the old leader
- Leave when you're done.
to bring me back from Xi'an.
You need to mind your work attitude.
Letting a little power go to your head.
Okay.
Then you can go.
All right, let's wait and see.
Dad, listen to me.
This is really not a misunderstanding.
We've already made it clear.
Dad.
Just leave my business alone.
Zhang Ziming,
where are you?
But we can imagine.
If we develop the spacecraft's
autonomous orbit measurement methods
and real-time orbit determination capabilities,
wouldn't it
greatly reduce the risk of the mission?
Could you
elaborate on this for us?
Let's just enjoy our meal today.
We will have plenty of opportunities to cooperate in the future.
Alright then.
These noodles are too spicy.
Are they?
I'm not very good with spicy food.
Zhang Ziming.
Jia.
You guys go ahead and eat.
This way.
Did you call my dad?
What right do you have to make that call?
No, is there a problem?
What do you think?
This is between the two of us.
Is it necessary to drag them into it?
I think it's necessary
to let your parents know about this.
It's also about politeness and respect.
Then have you ever respected me?
I don't think there's anything wrong with what I said.
I did this
for the sake of our future.
I hope you don't misunderstand me.
There's no misunderstanding.
You made your point very clear.
Let's just leave it at that.
Don't pester me anymore.
Jiajia.
What are you doing?
Why aren't you working?
I'm just cleaning up.
Getting familiar with the place.
Jiajia.
Just say it.
Are you done with your work?
I bought you some milk tea.
Half sugar, less ice, new flavor.
Try it.
Thanks.
Are you upset about something, Jia?
Don't worry.
There's nothing
a cup of milk tea can't fix.
If there is, then
buy two.
No, no, no.
You've been quite proactive lately.
That's good.
I'm just trying to create
a good working environment for you seniors.
It's the least I can do.
Jia.
Yesterday, I happened to see
an orbit design you made years ago.
That's our Jia.
It perfectly illustrates
the intellectual beauty of the women at Muxing,
academic beauty,
and exploratory beauty.
Why do I feel more and more
that you're up to no good?
No.
I'm completely sincere, Sister Jia.
My admiration
and respect for you
come straight from the bottom of my heart,
endless like a flowing river.
Okay, okay, okay.
Stop talking.
I'm really not used to you being like this.
It's fine, Sister Jia.
You'll get used to it.
I'll still need a lot of
your help with work in the future.
Since you didn't charge me any tuition,
I've already gotten a great deal.
You really don't need to exaggerate so much.
As for work matters,
you can ask me anytime.
Got it, Sister Jia.
Sister Jia, Sister Jia, Sister Jia!
I suddenly remembered.
I heard you guys made an orbital plan
for a solar system exploration satellite before,
right?
Can I take a look?
Why the sudden interest?
Nothing.
It's just that even though we're part of the mission,
we can't slack off.
I want to use it as a reference
and learn from it.
It's good that you have this intention.
But
that was just an experimental preliminary plan.
If you want to learn,
you still need to do the data calculations at hand well.
Definitely.
Isn't it the more, the merrier, Sister Jia?
Sister Jia, just let us see it.
Let us experience it and learn from it.
Alright, alright.
Role model.
Alright.
You're making yourself dizzy shaking your head like that.
This requires permission,
so I'll approve it for you.
You don't have to do this in the future.
It's good that you want to learn.
Just say it directly.
Understood.
Alright.
Take this ID number
and register at the computing center.
Thank you, Sister Jia.
Wait a minute.
Remember what I said.
This is not the most important thing.
Work comes first.
Definitely.
Jiajia, this noon...
Zhang Ziming,
I've said all I need to say.
Can you stop looking for me?
Jiajia.
It's like this.
I think regarding your parents,
you might have misunderstood.
I don't want to pressure you.
I just think that
since we've been together for so long,
we should at least give our families an explanation.
I will talk to my parents myself.
Stop flattering yourself, okay?
It's been so many days.
Can't we just talk calmly?
There's no need.
I have to work. Go back to your business.
Guys.
Jia gave me the access.
Bao didn't get slapped for nothing.
He did a great job.
I told you it would work.
Have a seat, Mr. Bao.
I saw Zhang Ziming
go look for Jia just now.
Jia's boyfriend.
That's him?
What? Any gossip?
No, no, no.
I just think
he is not that good.
Don't underestimate him.
He's an aerospace elite.
They happen to be doing a mission together this time.
The young couple fights side by side to overcome difficulties
and improve their relationship.
Stop gossiping and go to the computer room.
Once we get all the data,
we can start working on the plan.
It's useful,
but we can't use it too much.
Nan,
great news.
Come.
Let me tell you something.
Jia
has approved our access.
The missing data will be filled in soon.
Now that the data is ready,
can we start designing
our plan?
Okay, I didn't expect Jia to actually approve it.
Of course.
Although Jia didn't say it out loud,
she was actually quite pleased.
We got her.
With a little trick,
the data is back in our hands.
I hope this project design
goes smoothly.
You.
Caibao,
what are you doing?
Jia.
Yan.
Where is Wu Wei?
Wei.
The competition was my idea.
It has nothing to do with the others.
Jia.
I really shouldn't have lied to you about the permissions.
I'm sorry.
But that's a separate matter.
Participation in this competition is voluntary.
We don't have any rules against it.
Before we entered the competition,
we had already made up our minds.
We will only use our free time
to do this.
Besides,
we are participating in this competition
just to train ourselves.
There is no rule saying you can't participate in competitions.
But in our industry,
the more basic things are, the more important they are.
I know what you're thinking.
You just failed the flight simulation,
and want to regain your pride through the competition, right?
You are trying to run before you can walk.
In the end, the loss outweighs the gain.
Since I am in charge of you,
and I have promised Mr. Qin,
I must take this responsibility.
And let me remind you,
there's an assessment during the probation period.
You doing this now,
what are you trying to do?
None of you want to stay here anymore?
Mr. Li, don't completely write them off.
I think we can't blame them entirely.
It must be hard for them after failing the simulated flight.
Their intention to seize an opportunity is good.
How about this?
Send me the orbit data you calculated.
We sent it to the intranet.
Why is there still a third of it not calculated?
We will finish it according to the schedule.
You need to understand clearly,
in this industry,
there is no such thing as finishing according to schedule.
Will the launch window wait for you?
Aerospace is all about racing against time.
Look,
you haven't even done your own job well,
and you still have the mind to participate in competitions.
Who taught you this?
Fine.
Since you have so much energy to spare,
starting from today,
I will assign daily tasks
to make sure your excess energy
is fully utilized.
I will check your progress every day.
As for the competition,
I will talk to Director Cao
and withdraw from it.
Before eight on Monday,
I'll be waiting for your first round of assignments.
Get to work.
Qu Ruonan.
I've told you everything I had to say.
You figure it out yourself.
What do we do now, guys?
Stop thinking about what to do.
Think about the assignment Jia mentioned
and what we should do about it.
Why are you looking at me?
Don't you always have the most ideas?
Not this time.
Didn't Sister Jia say
to finish our work properly before talking about anything else?
Yeah.
With this much data,
it'd be good enough to just finish the assignment.
Doesn't Chu Jiajia just want
to force us to withdraw from the competition?
Not only will I not withdraw, I will participate.
And I will even complete the assignment she gave us
beautifully.
Give me more of the data to calculate.
I'll handle it.
Forget it, let's just distribute it evenly.
I said I'll handle it, so I'll handle it.
Whether you believe me or not.
Let's not. If we're handling it, we handle it together.
We'll all work overtime together.
It's too late. Time to get off work.
I find you really...
Didn't you say you'd handle it?
Let's go back and pull an all-nighter together.
Then let's handle it together.
Then let's do it.
Let's do it.
Then let's all handle it.
What's so hard about that?
Whether we pull an all-nighter
or not, we're staying up.
Let's just do it together.
It's a new day.
Go Team Muxing!
Qi,
did you really stay up all night?
Look at Qi,
and then look at yourself.
Is the new cup working out for you?
Nan is asking you a question.
How's the new cup?
Isn't it better than the one that broke?
I think the old one was better.
The style and color of this cup are too tacky.
I think it looks great.
Really.
Such a tacky color.
Forget it. You can't cure bad taste.
Brother.
She kindly gave you a mug.
And you're being so picky.
Pour it yourself.
I'm not being picky.
It's ugly.
That's an objective fact.
An objective fact.
Then don't use it.
If you don't like it, throw it away.
You really bite the hand that feeds you.
No one is forcing you to use it.
Ying Ziqi, did you take the wrong medicine?
Nan kindly gave you a gift.
It's fine if you don't like it.
But you didn't have to say things to break her heart.
It's okay. Um.
I just remembered I have something to do.
I'll head back first.
Didn't you give me the mug?
Me giving you a gift? What are you thinking?
You're flattering yourself.
You broke my mug.
Shouldn't you replace it?
Didn't you make it clear to him?
I told you.
I came back from drinking that day and gave you the cup,
and told you it was from Nan.
Right.
Then I made a mistake.
It's fine.
Everyone has different tastes.
So this cup was a gift from Nan.
This cup,
you gave it to Qi, didn't you?
I knew it. That day in the pantry,
you kept fiddling with Qi's cup.
Qu Ruonan,
could it be that you...
Caibao.
I'm leaving first.
I...
Are you really mad?
Go away.
Nan.
Are you really mad?
She is mad.
To be exact,
this should be called
awkwardness.
Dumbfounded, huh?
It's all your fault.
Are you seriously shifting the blame to me?
When others give it, it looks good.
But when I give it, it's ugly, right?
Besides,
isn't it an objective fact that it's ugly?
What should I do then?
Although I don't really get it.
But Qi,
according to standard procedure,
shouldn't you hurry to catch up to her
to apologize and explain?
You must apologize.
Be sincere about it.
Don't ruin the team's unity at this critical moment.
Stop staring and go.
Run.
Keep it up.
Hello, a glass of water, please.
Okay.
What I said earlier,
I hope you didn't take it to heart.
I misunderstood.
I didn't know you gave me the cup.
It's fine.
Like I said,
everyone's taste is different.
Hello, your water.
Thanks.
I thought Wu Wei gave me the cup.
He didn't make it clear.
We're used to being sharp-tongued.
So,
you're not angry, are you?
No, no, no.
Why would I be angry?
What I said earlier
was all a joke.
If there's nothing else, I'll go first.
And,
thank you for the chocolate last time.
Chocolate?
I mean, after the simulated flight control reset,
the chocolate you gave me.
Um...
Actually, what you said that time
was quite useful.
So for this orbital competition,
I want to participate properly.
Let's work hard together.
Um, you guys discuss it first today.
I'll go home and think about the algorithm.
Remember to use the water cup.
Okay.
I'm leaving. Bye.
Bye.
Jiajia.
Wait a minute.
I found some books at home.
I don't know if they're yours,
so I brought them for you.
Thank you.
I've reflected on myself these past few days.
I shouldn't have ignored your feelings.
I apologize.
Actually, I don't want to just give up.
Our relationship of so many years
hasn't been easy.
It really hasn't been easy all these years.
But what exactly are you thinking?
Can we talk?
I don't know what to say.
I just feel
quite regretful
and like a failure.
At work,
I can calculate
the orbit of a satellite tens of thousands of kilometers away.
I can overcome
one problem and glitch after another.
But when it comes to relationships,
I am truly powerless.
I don't know how to describe it.
It's just this feeling
of being powerless
and disappointed.
Whether it's towards myself, you,
or this relationship.
Do you remember this book?
I remember back then...
It should be Haoyue-3.
It was our first collaboration,
and we encountered technical difficulties right from the start.
To overcome this problem,
we stayed up day and night for months.
We constantly tested and revised our ideas.
At the toughest moment,
I gave this book to you.
It's my favorite sci-fi novel.
The mission went smoothly after that.
I remember after the celebration party,
I confessed my feelings to you.
Yeah.
Everything felt so wonderful back then.
Because we had a common goal,
a common dream.
We both loved aerospace and longed for space.
I guess we were kindred spirits.
But I don't know since when,
everything changed.
It seems like many things
were slowly worn away by reality
and disappeared.
It's really a shame.
I think the problem between us might be
that what I consider important,
you don't care about.
And what we want from each other,
we just can't give.
So there is really no need
to keep draining each other.
I'm sorry.
There's no need to say sorry either.
Let's just leave it at this.
Jiajia.
Can I have this book,
"Rendezvous with Rama"?
This book was meant for you
if you had opened it.
Dafu, Chashao,
how are things on your end?
Master Ying,
I've uploaded the data for you.
I sent mine to you first.
I sent mine too.
I sent mine too, Qi.
I think it's ready.
Upload it.
The scoring starts now.
The scores are updated in real time.
What place is this?
Fifty.
Fifth place.
We are in fifth place.
Wei, Wei, fifth!
We won.
We are in fifth place.
I'd like to see
who dares to underestimate us now.
This is what they call becoming famous overnight.
Let's celebrate properly.
Celebrate!
Our joy has turned to sorrow a bit too quickly.
They used this satellite toolkit to optimize the data.
I've seen their plan.
Their approach is basically the same as ours,
or perhaps ours is even better.
But in terms of score,
it's hard for us to surpass.
The difference between our plan and theirs
lies in data optimization.
This toolkit is very powerful.
Whether it has been optimized or not
makes a world of difference in the results.
So we can't use this software?
We can't. Only they can use it.
That's not right.
I remember according to previous international conventions,
this type of software toolkit
can be shared internationally.
The software we developed and designed
has also been fully shared.
That's us.
They are not that kind.
They used to share it,
but after we announced the Haoyue Project,
they stopped sharing.
It's banned for us.
All foreigners can use it,
only we can't.
If the data is not optimized,
our plan is useless no matter how well it is done.
This is too much.
Is this too much?
Is this just too much?
This is shameless. This is despicable.
This is dirty.
This is technological competition.
It's always been a game of catch-up.
This isn't the first time.
We still have to prove ourselves with our skills.
It's just data.
Can't we just calculate it ourselves?
Wei.
Are you trying to finish it with your courage and perseverance?
Didn't our predecessors
figure it out using an abacus?
Wei.
It's impossible for us to finish.
The amount of data is just too massive.
With just the four of us
working day and night without rest,
even when the competition ends,
we might not be able to finish it.
What if we could apply for
a supercomputer?
A supercomputer?
Don't you know the new Director Gu
spends all day in the computer center?
He's been here for days without any progress.
If we run into him there,
wouldn't that be asking for trouble?
Think of a way.
What for?
We're in an academic competition,
and we have some data that
needs to be optimized by the supercomputer.
Who sent you here?
We came here ourselves.
Who is your advisor?
Qin Bojun, Mr. Qin.
Alright.
Thank you so much.
What kind of competition requires a week's use?
Why don't you ask me
to lend you the computer room?
Let me tell you,
if you were competing to land on the far side of the moon,
I would even let you have my seat.
Stop messing around and get out of here.
Mr. Gu, please calm down.
Young people don't know any better.
Let's go.
Sorry to bother you.
I was just looking for you.
Are you still busy?
Go back early when you're done.
Why? Are you going to do my work for me?
Come on, you do it.
Okay, I'll help you with the work.
Why are you so good to me?
Alright, I know you care about me.
Lately,
you've been working overtime for me and stuff.
There's only a little work left.
I'll go back when I'm done.
Hurry back.
Okay.
Still not leaving? Want to stay with me?
Those guys from the Muxing team
have really grown some nerve.
They don't take me seriously at all.
What's wrong?
Check the group chat.
I didn't plan to let them participate before.
But they insisted.
Now their terrible results are embarrassing me.
No, I have to get an explanation.
Do they still want to stay in flight control?
Jiajia.
Don't be mad.
These kids really went too far.
Everything can be discussed.
There's nothing to discuss.
We were too easy on them before.
Now we need to keep them in line.
Talk it over properly.
Why is everyone just standing around?
It's such a mess.
In this environment,
how can you make anything good?
Jia, we'll clean up in a bit.
Look at your faces.
You all look like you just got out of a hard labor camp.
Don't you want to live?
People who don't know
would think we are evil landlords,
bullying you poor tenants.
The data verification is finally over.
Why don't you take a rest?
Aren't you tired?
Don't you care about your health?
We do.
But we are not tired.
We can keep going.
I'm sorry, Jia.
It was my idea to enter the competition secretly.
I submitted the proposal myself.
Actually, Jia, it was us.
Let him speak.
This has nothing to do with them.
I did it all by myself.
Just come at me.
Well done, Mr. Wu.
Come down here.
The names of the spacecraft and related missions in this drama have been fictionalized.
Ying Deqian, He Qiang
Chen Bing
Zhao Qiangjun
Wu Jianguo
Xiao Bai
Li Jiaming, Liu Zhenguo, Wang Caimao, Liu Tiancheng, Liu Lan, Zhao Shufeng, Bai Yuqin, An Chengzhi
Wang Yiqi, Feng Shuaige, Tang Zixuan, Fu Jingyun, Wang Zhenglin, Qin Dehang, Zhang Haoming, Wang Zihan
Production Team
Line Producer Zhao Xuguang
Lighting Team
Gaffer
Sound Recordist
Painter
Producer
Makeup & Hair Team
Data Management Li Peiyuan, Tong Zhenzhong
Legal Team
Equipment Support
Beijing Liushun Huihuang Film and Television Media Co., Ltd.
Beijing Chuangxiang Xinshijie Film and Television Culture Co., Ltd.
Negative Cutter
VFX Production Company
Beijing Ziyou Xunhuan Digital Technology Co., Ltd.
VFX Supervisor Zhang Zheng
Beijing Moying Dongli Culture Media Co., Ltd.
Packager
Compositor
Dubbing Team
Bianjiang Studio
Music Production Team
Theme Song 'Mu Xing'
Vocals
Lyrics
Poster Design Team
Special Thanks
Tianjin Xingye Real Estate Group Co., Ltd.
Tianjin Jingmao Metal Products Co., Ltd.
Publicity Department of Nankai District Committee, Tianjin
Publicity Department of Jinghai District Committee, Tianjin
Jingwumen Zhonghua Wulin Park
Jizhou Cheshenjia Scenic Area
Guiding Organization
News and Publicity Center of China National Space Administration
Zhengzhou New Power Film Co., Ltd.
Horgos New Power Film and Television Culture Co., Ltd.